<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Varahi</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_navigation">navigation</string>
    <string name="Paragraph">Dear All,\n
        Wishing you all a Very Happy and Prosperous Deepavali !!\n\n

The Deepavali festival dates for this year are as follows:\n
Deepavali – 27th October\n
Lakshmi Poojai –  28th October\n
Bali Paadyami –  29th October\n\n

        <b>Yama Deepam</b>\n
First day of Deepavali is called KAALA RATHRI and we should light this Yama deepam on that day to get rid of YAMA BAYAM, accidental deaths (akaala maranangal) etc  - and pray for SRI NEELA SARASWATHI (Wife of Sri Uchishta Ganapathi) . This deepam should be lit after 6.30 pm on that day and it should remain till next day morning on the day of Deepavali.\n\n

        <b>Yama Tharpanam</b>\n
This tharpanam has to be performed on the Deepavali day . This can be done by all whether they have father, mother .This will protect us from untoward accident, akaala maranam, increase of life span, subhiksham and prosperity .\n\n

On the Day of Deepavali after taking your bath and completing Sandhya Vandanam, everyone should do Yama Tharpanam before 7 am facing east.\n\n

        <b>Sankalpam</b>\n
“Aasvayuja krishna paksha chathurdhasee punyakaale yama tharpanam karishye”\n\n

        Tharpanam should be done with Yagnopaveetham (Poonal ) on <b>RIGHT side </b> ONLY and with Shobana Akshadhai (Manjal Kalanda Arisi). Pure water to be used for tharpanam.\n
(Please note  - NO ELLU and Yagnopaveetham NOT on Left Side)\n\n

        This tharpanam can be done by all the people. <b>People who are having parents also can do this tharpanam</b>\n\n

        <b>Tharpana Manthram: (East Facing)</b>\n
1.	Yamaya Namaha – Yamam Tharpayami\n
2.	Dharmaraajaya Namaha – Dharmaraajam Tharpayami\n
3.	Mruthyave Namaha – Mruthyam Tharpayami\n
4.	Anthakaaya Namaha – Anthakam Tharpayami\n
5.	Vaivaswathaaya Namaha – Vaivaswatham Tharpayami\n
6.	Kaalaaya Namaha – Kaalam Tharpayami\n
7.	Sarva Bhootha Kshayaaya Namaha – Sarva Bhootha Kshayam Tharpayami\n
8.	Authumbaraaya Namaha – Authumbaram Tharpayaami\n
9.	Thathnaaya Namaha – Thathnam Tharpayami\n
10.	Neelaaya Namaha – Neelam Tharpayami\n
11.	Parameshtine Namaha – Parameshtinam Tharpayami\n
12.	Vrukotharaaya Namaha – VrukotharamTharpayami\n
13.	Chitraaya Namaha – Chitram Tharpayami\n
14.	Chitra Guptaaya Namaha – Chitra Guptam Tharpayami\n\n

After completing yama tharpanam, please chant the below sloka and pray Yamadharma Raja by facing south:\n
        <b> Yamo Nihanthaa Pithru, Dharma Raajo Vaivaswatho Dhandarascha Kaala prethaathi Proththa Kruthaanthakaari kruthaantha Yethath dasakruth japanthi neela parvatha sangaasa rudra gopa samuthbhava kaala dhandathara sriman vaivaswatha Namosthuthe !</b>\n\n\n
Vaarahi Kumar
</string>
</resources>
